What does it take to become a legend?
Christy is a history, drama film directed by David Michôd.
Christy Martin never imagined life beyond her small-town roots in West
Virginia—until she discovered a knack for punching people.
Fueled by grit, raw determination, and an unshakable desire to win, she charges into the world
of boxing under the guidance of her trainer and manager-turned-husband, Jim.
But while Christy flaunts a fiery persona in the ring, her toughest battles unfold outside
it—confronting family, identity, and a relationship that just might become life-or-death.
Christy Martin, played by Sydney Sweeney.
James V. Martin, played by Ben Foster.
Joyce Salters, played by Merritt Wever.
Lisa Holewyne, played by Katy O'Brian.
John Salters, played by Ethan Embry.
Rosie, played by Jess Gabor.
Christy is a 2025 American biographical sports drama film directed by David Michôd, written by Michôd and Mirrah
Foulkes, and starring Sydney Sweeney, Ben Foster, Merritt Wever, Katy O'Brian, Ethan Embry, and Chad L.
The film chronicles the rise of former professional boxer Christy Martin (Sweeney) to becoming America's
best-known female boxer in the 1990s, and later her coach-turned-husband's 2010 attempted murder of her.
The film had its world premiere at the 2025 Toronto International Film
Festival on September 5, 2025, in the Special Presentations section.
It was released theatrically on November 7, 2025, by Black Bear Pictures, earning $1.3 million in its opening weekend in the United States,
which Box Office Mojo classified as one of the top 12 worst openings for a new release that opened on over 2,000 screens.
As a result, the film has been considered a box-office bomb.
It opened at #11 at the box office, outside the top
ten, and fell to #23 by its second week.
The film received mixed reviews from critics,
though the performances were praised.
The film explores themes of attempted murder, based on true story,
west virginia, domestic violence, female boxing.
The tone is emotional.